[Music]
my personal favorite point in click
adventure is Indiana Jones and the fate
of Atlantis I always love the franchise
Steve and George created and you can
clearly see that kind of love in this
game look at this box art from the year
1992 you can get this with digital
downloads nowadays but yeah kids I am
quite old already so first let me show
you the result and see for yourself if
it somehow invokes the feeling you had
when you play this game all including
the famous Indiana Jones color cycled
Splash banner and pixel art pre-credits
role
[Music]
a
all right Sophia now what kind of
interesting notes did you find in the
officer's mess Mr Jones after you were
sleeping off our romantic moment I
searched the quarters for Clues what
occult AR s they were looking for and
that's why we steered the boat to Sicily
yes Indie they were looking for the
biblical artifact called The Ring of
Solomon ridiculous this does not exist
this was always a bedtime story my
father told me just before I went to
sleep you said the same thing about
Atlantis and you did not believe me then
okay okay well while we are here anyway
we can at least have some fish and
chips a typical Indiana Jones Adventure
game or movie is not complete without a
map showing the flight to Barnett
College that is fictionally located in
New York so here we go
[Music]
the opening sequence with the banner and
all had a cinematic feel and in an
aspect ratio that was not custom in
these days so let's show a typical
Barnett College interaction between
Indie and another character in something
that looks like
320x 200 pixels
wide Ben wait a minute
what can I do for you you are exactly
the one I need um I am a little bit
Rusty on my understanding of Hebrew I'd
hope you could help me with this ancient
text here ah let me see well this talks
about the hotam schlomo meaning ring of
Solomon where did you find this well I
didn't Marcus did he was a little bit
hungry actually probably he got lost in
his own library for days a typical
Marcus brilliant man but a little bit
absentminded from time to time this man
script tells about the immense Powers
the bearer of the Ring possesses it
gives the power to command demons genies
and the ability to talk to animals H
demons that's why the axis are so
interested in possessing this
ring I even made a special a gradient
points Editor to be able to produce the
pixel art scaling map used in the fade
of Atlantis and other LucasArts
games I was inspired by the way how many
of the adventure game Studio games
handles these as I looked into the
assets that came along with the exported
games I saw that they used a grayscale
gradient map the points that I plotted
in the editor are interpolated into the
scaling map when exported the gradient
map has the same aspect ratio as the
source image but is much much smaller it
does not need more pixels than there is
necessary needed to look up the scaling
the scaling value is looked up and
corresponds to the position the walkable
character is in it works surprisingly
well I might
say the professor character that is
called Ben was a new pixel art character
generated with civit AI the bobbing head
and mouth animation is still something
that I needed to do myself and as I am a
better coder than being an artist this
did not lead to the Quality talk
animation I was hoping for
if I compare it to the ripped Sprite
sheet from the real fade of Atlantis
game trademarked of
course but I'm not complaining as this
is way better than I could produce from
scratch I know that a bunch of pixel
artists are mad at people that use AI
tools to make this but as I am a single
Army hobby developer I cannot afford to
pay an artist I strongly believe that
professional pixel art artist still can
keep their job as it far superior than
generated a bunch of characters but AI
tools like stable diffusion and others
are not going away and I am planning to
make a pixel art model sourced from the
60 plus pixel art characters I handrawn
myself in the last 3 years and this is
something what graphical artists could
do to to make the volume of work that is
expected to be in a game I promis this
Dev log to be some sort of demonstration
how I was able to create Lucas art style
pixel art characters and matching
backgrounds so here we go I was
wondering if I could make a Qui-Gon Jedi
character in Lucas art style as I happen
to know that Lucas Arts did not create a
point and click adventure similar to
fade of Atlantis for the Star Wars
franchise that is a shame of course
although the action game are great by
the way another character I always
wanted to create is Henry Jones the
annoying father of Indiana Jones this
character was in the Last Crusade point
and click game of course but that was in
very low resolution so that could use
some um pimping it is often a hit or a
Miss especially if it turns out to turn
into a closeup instead of a standing
pose that I wanted initially but but
that's because of the noise seed in the
models generation this the way these
models work let's speed things up a
notch because the civid AI takes its
time especially the flux models like the
Dig backgrounds I settled with a nice
Lucas art style rendering that has a
good neutral pose and one that also has
a great facial expression once in pixaki
I tried to get rid of the hard edges
that are sometimes on the character what
I learned by doing pixel artart for
quite some time is that light usually
comes from above and causes a subtle Rim
light for the character these are the
shoulders that would get some light
adding a black bow tie makes him look
quite like Henry Jones senior eventually
I ended up pimping up the original pixel
art character from The Last Crusade and
transferred the pallette from Indiana to
Henry I added an umbrella that became
famous in the movie because brought down
an enemy airplane by scaring the birds
those birds turned out to be fatal to
the German pilot that fatally crashed
into the flock of birds if you haven't
seen that scene you should watch the
clip or better the entire movie you
won't be
disappointed so after several attempts
and prompt tweaks using the civid AI
tool the tool generated quite a
good-looking Star Wars Jedi character so
first thing to do now is to remove the
background there is a small gradient in
the background that is not too hard for
photoshop with the smart removal tool I
fixed some small issues but it is
evident that I should not go overboard
with this because I need to scale it
down to manageable pixel sizes
first after that I can use my favorite
pixel art tool called pixaki and make it
look great
the nice thing about using a Mac is that
it is easy to copy from the Mac to the
pixaki app this way I can make a blank
canvas with the right pixel dimensions
first then copy on the Mac and then hit
paste in pixaki and behold I can start
tweaking on my tne planet I wanted to
replace the background with the sky of
another render that looked much better
so I did some touch-up work in Photoshop
also the Dome shaped house had wear
entrance so that needed some love too
with the help of the generative
capabilities in Photoshop I could easily
remov unwanted Parts the nice thing with
this generative process is that it gives
you three options to choose from there
is always one that suits the scene and
otherwise you can always regenerate
again
well let's see the final resulting scene
with a well-known Sith
Lord and let's see how the scene looks
like with a background generated by the
flux model called The Dig background art
Lucas Arts game Indie and Henry talk
with each other other as they are
located at the residence of retired
Professor called Henry Jones
senior Dad I need your excellent
biblical knowledge of religious
artifacts what do you happen to know
about the ring of Solomon so you finally
agree that there might be some truth to
all these bedtime stories Legend says
that the demon disguises King Solomon
acquired a ring and Solomon lost his
throne somehow the ring returned to him
when he came to his sensus again it is
believed that the ring was buried in his
Royal grave some centuries later some
grave robber stole the ring from the
grave and sold it to a rich Merchant
this Merchant gave it to his wife that
was able to use its power somehow how
did she loose the ring often she talked
and gained a lot of useful information
by talking to the croch however one time
she forgot to give them breadcrumbs one
crow was very angry and pulled off the
ring when she was asleep in the Valley
from then on the ring was never found
again probably it is on the bottom of
the sea it seems like a dead end to
me so that wraps it up for now please
hit the like And subscribe as it helps
me stay motivated to make these nice
videos and join me again when I release
a new Dev
log the next Dev log will be about the
implementation of dialogues in point and
click games I will look back at the chat
mapper format as that was my choice to
make dialogues possible in the game The
Lost
adventures also I will show you some old
footage of the features the old dialogue
web editor had great fun to see how I
did this 12 years ago it will also give
me a way do a bit of retrospection on
the strengths and weaknesses of chat
mapper I will also definitely show off
the new way of supporting dialogues in
pixel parody the choice that I made was
the open-source ink format and Inky
editor of course I will show some funny
dialogues in pixel parody without
spoilers bye and see you next time